New York Medical Union Records
New York Medical Union Records
1865-1938
New York Medical Union
1 linear foot (1 box)
Mss.arc
New York Academy of Medicine Library. Rare Book Room.
Historical Statement
The New York Medical Union was founded in 1865 as the East River Medical Association. The original object of the organization was to exchange views regarding the regulation of medical practice in the eastern section of New York City. Monthly meetings were held in this regard, and for discussion of cases and journal articles. The name was changed to the New York Medical Union in 1884.
Scope and Content
The majority of the collection is comprised of minutes from New York Medical Union (East River Medical Association prior to 1884) meetings between 1865 and 1938. Also included are printed lists of Officers and Members for 1879, 1882-1892.
Arrangement of Collection
Records are in chronological order and mostly comprised of meeting minutes in several notebooks.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of The New York Academy of Medicine Library. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
New York Medical Union; Medicine -- New York (State) -- New York -- Societies; East River Medical Association
Container List
- New York Medical Union
  - Minutes, 1865-1869 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1869-1879 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1880-1884 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1880-1886 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lists of Officers and Members, 1879, 1882-1892 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lists of Members and Minutes, 1890-1892 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1892-1906 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1927-1935 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
Provenance
New York Medical Union.